Pushpender

Gurgaon, Haryana
+91 82855 17996

pushpender673@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/pushpender673

Career Summary

- → Having around 5 years of industry experience in developing web application with Java.
- → Worked with Spring (Boot, data, webflux, batch), ORM Framework Hibernate and Spring Cloud (For Implementing Microservices Architecture)

Technical Skills

Primary Skill	Java, Data Structure & Algorithm
Secondary Skills	Spring (Boot + Cloud), Micronaut (For microservices), Kafka, Aerospike, Junit Testing, Spring webflux, Redis, Cassandra
Frontend Skills	ReactJS, Jest Enzyme, GraphQL, Apollo client, jQuery, JavaScript/Typescript, HTML/CSS
Databases	MySQL, MS SQL, PostgreSQL
Others	Git/SVN, Agile Development, Gradle/Maven, AWS ECS, Docker, CI/CD using Jenkins, Linux

Work Experience

Olx Group, Gurgaon- Haryana

April 2022 to Present

Software Engineer II

→ Involved in designing and implementing the final solution for various features.

Airtel International LLP, Gurgaon- Haryana

April 2021 to Mar 2022

Senior Software Engineer

- → Worked on various challenging projects through which got exposure to various technologies like Spring Web flux, Spring Batch, Kafka, Redis, etc
- → Written a bulk data processing microservice do perform recharges from given csv file.
- → Written a generic framework to write backend to frontend layer by defining specs in a JSON file.
- → Involved in designing and implementing the final solution for various features.

Application Developer

- → Working with a banking project where developed an application for their business customers so that they can apply for quick simple business loans.
- → Followed TDD with Junit for backend and Jest+Enzyme for Frontend application with Pair Programming.
- → Writing frontend using React with hooks and typescript, apollo client for GraphQL and Micronaut for backend to frontend layer.
- → Setting up infrastructure on AWS for containerized application and configuring CI/CD with Jenkins

Unify Technologies Pvt Ltd, Gurgaon- Haryana

April 2019 to July 2019

Software Development Engineer

Client - Airtel Payment Bank, Gurgaon

- → Improved the delay in receiving OTPs by customers.
- → Involved in day-to-day dev activities like implementation, designing and deploying application.

Oodles Technologies Pvt Ltd

Sept 2017 to Mar 2019

Associate Consultant

Client - Truno (Business Intelligence App) - An application for store sellers through which they can analyses their sales data and can take informative decision.

- → Developed a Microservice to cater frontend application with required REST APIs and other microservices.
- → Gathering requirements from client and writing SRS document.
- → Designed the workflow of the application with the collaboration of team members.
- → Involved in Defect solving and testing bugs in testing environment.

Client - MFG/ LiveSource (Supplier Management Tool) - Sourcing Professionals and Engineers Can Quickly, Intelligently and Securely Perform Supplier Discovery, Post RFQs and Get Competitive Quotes.

- → Revamped the RFQ section to improve the traffic and customer experience.
- → Developed a dedicated module for a specific supplier and integrated with current application.
- → Created stored procedures which includes business rules for data validation.

Education

B. TECH, COMPUTER SCIENCE / University of Delhi

2017

77.9 % aggregate

SENIOR SECONDARY (HSC) / Vidya Mandir Public School, Faridabad 90.33% aggregate

2013

Personal Information

Name Pushpender

Father Name Mr. Vijay Singh

Date of Birth 19th-July-1996

Languages Known English and Hindi

Nationality Indian

Current Address E-673, S.G.M Nagar near hanuman mandir sec-48, Faridabad-

121001 (HR)